Not a sound. Not a warning. Not a chance. Not alone.
Red Planet is a thriller, action, science fiction
film directed by Antony Hoffman.
Astronauts search for solutions to save a dying Earth by searching
on Mars, only to have the mission go terribly awry.
Robby Gallagher, played by Val Kilmer.
Cmdr. Kate Bowman, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Lt. Ted Santen, played by Benjamin Bratt.
Dr. Quinn Burchenal, played by Tom Sizemore.
Chip Pettengill, played by Simon Baker.
Dr. Bud Chantilas, played by Terence Stamp.
Red Planet is a 2000 science fiction action film directed by Antony Hoffman.
The film stars Val Kilmer, Carrie-Anne Moss, and Tom Sizemore.
The plot follows a team of astronauts who search for solutions to save a dying
Earth by searching on Mars, only to have the mission go terribly awry.
Red Planet was released in the United States on 10 November 2000.
The film was a critical failure and a box-office bomb, only grossing $33.5 million
against the budget of $80 million and is Hoffman's only feature film to date.
Red Planet was one of two films released in 2000 that depicted an expedition to Mars;
the other was Mission to Mars, which was released eight months earlier.
The film explores themes of future, planet mars, robot, astronaut, space opera.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.